''a''
''e''
''i''
''pa''
''na''
''kotchay''
strong
''karshiya''
in front
Mehmet, tell us if you'll come
and carry the wood tomorrow.
Hello?
There's no signal...
Emine! There's no signal here,
what do you want?
The minibus is coming!
My son Ahmet
is back from his military service!
Hey, Ahmet is back from the army!
Congratulations!
- Are you happy?
اiçek, congratulations!
Finally! Now we can organize
the wedding ceremonies!
Why are you sitting next to me?
Go away!
You're bad luck.
Don't come near me!
l don't want my kids
to be mute like you!
Well said, اiçek.
- Good girl.
Go to hell!
Mustafa, come back home, l need you!
l am at the café with Ahmet, l'm coming.
As long as you're not a soldier,
you're not a man yet.
And l found a wife who is worthy of me.
You did nothing, it was Feride
the matchmakerwho found her!
Hello Dad!
Hello daughter.
Are you heading back home?
Yes. How about a lentil soup for dinner?
Yes, it's been a while.
Fatma?
Could you set the table?
l'm busy right now.
Hello Dad.
l finished school earliertoday.
Dad?
Tomorrow night,
we'll congratulate اiçek.
l can go, right?
You can go.
But on one condition,
you must be home by nine.
Good night my daughter.
Good night dad.
Good night.
Hello Narin.
Have you seen Fuat?
No, l haven't seen him.
l was in the forest.
He'll return soon.
Are you still hunting the wolf?
He's smart...
He hides in the shadows.
Without leaving a trail...
The forest is too dangerous.
You mustn't go.
l have to do it.
ln the village, they'll thank me
once l bring them the dead wolf.
Have you seen Fuat?
No Narin, l still haven't seen him.
He'll be back soon.
Dad!
Ready?
Wait...
Go.
Great job my girl!
Wearthat headscarf appropriately.
But Didem wears it like this on TV...
How's this?
Better.
Look where you're going.
lf the Mayor doesn't show up
people are going to talk...
l'll go too, to congratulate the groom.
Matching youngsters is just my job,
you're neitherthe first northe last.
And if God grants you a boy,
you'll have a happy life.
No! Forthat, one must go to the Bride's Rock.
One must light a fire there.
You're crazy! We don't do ceremonies
at the Rock anymore.
Our men prevent us from going.
- The wolf is up there!
Dad!
Sibel, l'm here!
Here she is!
My daughter l was telling you about.
No one knows the area as well as her, if she
had seen anything she would have told me about it.
Right, daughter?
lt's my duty to help the State.
Let me treat you
to some coffee in the village.
Dad!
l need to go to the fields.
OK, fine.
Finally you're here. What time is it?
Dad?
اiçek called, she wants me
to meet up with her, can l go?
Now? No, it's too late.
Dad, it's really important,
all the girls are there...
Fatma, l won't repeat it!
And why is it she can go whenever she wants?!
Since you gave herthe rirfe she's always outside!
How dare you talk to me on that tone?
Go to your room!
Dad?
What?
No... Nothing, l...
l was going to do laundry.
Do you have any dirty shirts?
No, thank you my daughter...
Does he wake up a lot at night?
He does when he's hungry, and he sleeps
again straight after breastfeeding.
That's the way he'll grow up, my boy!
You don't look very well,
still yourfiancأ(Copyright) has arrived...
Ahmet...
He's a bit... How can l say?
Thin... l imagined him differently...
A bit taller... l don't know...
You found a good husband,
with a good job, you're lucky!
Do you want to end up alone like Narin,
that crazy old spinster?
Looking for something?
Talk.
Why won't you talk?
Am l scaring you?
Scared of you? You idiot!
lf it weren't for me,
you'd already be dead!
Sibel?
Yes Narin, it's me.
What's wrong?
lt can't be...
The wolf... Wolf.
l know it.
What do you mean, the wolf?
lt's the wolf.
That's him.
l need to go tell them...
No!
Don't!
You mustn't tell them...
They won't believe you.
They won't even listen to you.
They'll ask you:
where's the rest of its bones?
What's your name?
How should l call you?
My name is...
Ali.
And you?
Sibel.
l've got good news.
They've just asked for Fatma's hand.
What?
But she's too young!
She needs to go to school!
My daughter, Fatma is old enough to get married.
She'll end up getting married someday anyway...
Stop being a killjoy!
l don't need your jealousy!
Fatma! Respect your older sister!
l'm tired of her spoiled manners. Let her go,
we'll be better off the two of us, right?
Leave it!
Those plants don't do shit...
We need to sew it up...
What are those?
A wolf...
These are a wolfs bones?
And why are you washing them?
Proof.
Dead. Proof he's dead.
Stop it!
Do it.
What time is it?
Why are you back so late?
l was cutting wood for Narin.
l'll get cooking right away.
Sibel! The TV Show is starting!
l'm taking groceries to Narin.
Sibel?
Are you okay, my daughter?
Yes. l'm alright.
l can see something's wrong.
You leave forthe fields at dawn,
you come back late...
Hello Narin.
Have you seen Fuat?
No. l still haven't seen him.
He'll be back soon...
Before my wedding with Fuat...
We're going to hold the ceremony...
At the Bride's Rock...
Here it is...
At that moment,
this is the dress
that l'll be wearing.
lt's Fuat's favorite color.
We'll light the fire
at the bottom of the Rock.
Then...
We'll dance till dawn,
with all the girls.
What fire?
But not just anyone
can light that fire...
Men can't light it.
A woman
needs to go to the heart of the forest,
to look forthe fire.
Then she must walk
to the Bride's rock...
And that's when
all the women of the village,
drawn to the fire,
gather at the feet of the Rock.
And there, all the way up...
And there, all the way up,
they shine,
with the village at theirfeet.
What if the wolfs not dead?
You never know.
Take it.
Where did you get that rirfe?
From a man.
Your husband?
Your father?
What does he do, yourfather?
Military or policeman?
He stamps stuff...
A seal?
Mayor?
Yourfather is the village chief?
How do you say ''bones'' by whistling?
''Bones''.
''Wolfs skeleton''?
''Wolfs skeleton''.
''Wool ski lesson''.
What?
''Waffle simpleton''.
Come on, laugh.
ls there any tea left?
ls that OK?
l'm going to اiçek's
engagement ceremony.
What did you do?
What's this?
l'm...
- Shhh! Shut up!
Don't make it worse by whistling!
There's no place for you here!
Look at you!
Where did you find that lipstick?
Did you go through my stuff?
You're embarrassing me!
Go away!
You look like a child,
you've spread makeup everywhere!
Go away, you ridiculed me, get out!
Calm down...
Why am l hiding?
l don't want to do the Military Service.
l don't do warfor somebody else,
l do it for myself.
lt's different.
Do l scare you?
Sibel is not here?
She's still asleep.
What sleep!
Anyway. l come bearing good news.
True.
We still haven't thanked you properly.
They asked for Fatma's hand
in marriage and l said yes.
Thank you. You did this.
l'm not here for Fatma.
You know old Kemal,
in the neighboring village...
He just passed away, l went to
his funeral, may he rest in peace.
He has a daughter, l saw herthere.
Poor her, she also became a widow
when she was quite young.
lt broke my heart.
lt's tough.
Being such a young widow,
staying alone, it's hard.
How long has it been since Aynur
left you? God rest her soul.
l'm not alone. l have Sibel with me.
What l'm seeing is that
you're the one serving me tea.
The great chief of the village...
Sibel here, Sibel there...
Has she said the slightest word since
the bad fever she had when she was 5?
The whistling language...
You and me, we understand it. But then?
God forbid,
if something happened to you, what then?
l'm sorry for being franc...
But look at yourself.
Your clothes are all wrinkled.
l'm not the only one to say it,
the whole village is talking about it.
You should know.
With all due respect,
when did tradition change here?
How dare you insult a man like this?
lf l like someone, l'll tell you,
and you'll do as you're told.
Fine.
Stay stubborn like that.
But you should know...
The girl is beautiful.
Sibel, l must ask you something.
ls something wrong?
Where are you going?
The bones!
The bones, but what bones?
l need to find more!
You're obsessed with your bones,
with yourwolf...
You should see it: there is no wolf.
- Yes!
No!
- l'm telling you there is!
You're just a coward!
No one is holding you back here!
Come!
Come here!
Look.
Does this look like a wolf?
ls that a wolf? Look!
Look, l'm telling you!
Does this look like a wolfs bone?
lt's a human phalange! Human!
But you're too stupid to understand!
She was about to hunt a wolf.
Go on then!
Go hunt yourwolf.
Wait, l'll do it...
Leave me.
Go do the laundry.
This morning
there wasn't a single clean shirt.
How was it at Narin's today? ls she OK?
She still goes on about some Fuat.
Does he really exist?
l was quite young...
l don't rememberwell.
One day,
Narin ran away with that boy, Fuat.
Her brothers tracked them down fortwo days
and they came back with just Narin...
And Fuat?
l heard he abandoned Narin and ran away.
That's why she went crazy and
she's still waiting for him to come back.
That's what happens
when you don't listen to yourfather!
Why are you looking at me?
She's the one
secretly meeting men in the forest!
What?!
- Don't you dare lie!
l saw you in the forest!
What are you talking about?
lt's not true!
l followed you!
You went to see a man!
l saw you with my own eyes!
- You're the one who's lying!
Fatma!
How dare you say dreadful lies
about your sister? Get out of my sight!
Go away!
You liar!
You know, the old Muammer...
He says he saw partridges
next to his wood.
Let's go have a look togethertomorrow.
lf you stay here,
no one will know.
Hello Narin.
Here's Al...
Fuat...
l told you he'd come back.
Let's leave.
Could you do something for me?
l need an lD Card.
Yourfather, he's the mayor.
He must deal with the villagers'
administrative issues.
Could you do this for me?
Tomorrow.
Could you bring it tomorrow?
Fuck!
Where are you going?
To the fields...
Cover your head
before you leave the house.
Who's that stranger you met up with
in the mountains?
Answer!
What stranger?
Don't lie to us,
your sister saw you together.
She hasn't seen anything.
You may fool your father, but not us!
Are your brains working at last?
Whore!
Fooling around
in the mountain with terrorists!
What would your mother think, in her grave!
- Dirty whore!
Ali!
They know you're here!
Have you seen Ali?
Ali?
Have you seen him?
Today?
Fuat!
Have you seen Fuat?
He'll be back.
Don't worry.
He'll finally come back.
He'll come.
Ali! Answer me! Ali!
You're staying home.
But l have to go work in the fields...
Do as you're told.
Mister Mayor!
We need to talk to your daughter.
Tell us what you know
about that fugitive.
The deserter's name is Ali Demir,
he lives in lstanbul.
Where did he come from
when you met him? Talk!
l don't know.
She says she doesn't know,
Commander.
Did he tell you where he was going?
No, he didn't say.
She says no.
Listen to me.
Yourfather's honor is at stake here.
Since when
does this village help terrorists?
Tell us!
l don't know! Where he's from,
where he's going, l don't know anything!
Commander, my daughter doesn't know anything.
She would have told you!
This guy is dangerous forthe country,
he's a terrorist. Plus, he's armed.
Thank God you managed to stay alive.
ls he the one who did this to yourface?
No! He isn't dangerous!
He isn't even armed! lt's wrong!
Commander!
Commander, excuse my daughter.
You see, she's handicapped...
She's doesn't know right from wrong...
God made her like this.
Please forgive hertoo.
lf she tells you anything else,
please keep us posted.
Commander, wait, l'll take you back.
Where's the mayor?
Good evening
- Good evening.
Sorry to bother you so late, but our
family made an important decision.
Things have got worse. Our son...
With Fatma. We don't want to anymore...
l don't understand...
We don't want Fatma anymore.
People talk in the village, our honor is at stake.
We've come to collect
the gifts we gave her.
l understand.
Fatma.
- Dad...
Fatma!
- Dad say something, it's not my fault!
Fatma listen to me!
You dishonored yourfamily
and ruined your sister's life.
Go on, eat now...
In this building, the four terrorists...
The suspect who organized
the demonstration on Taksim square
Is called Ozgur Polat, 48.
Wanted...
The wanted suspect seems to be
affilliated to a terrorIst organizatIon.
Here's the report we made
with the suspect's family.
y daughter wouId never do thIs...
She's married, and she has a child
What's this story about terrorists,
bombs, have you all gone mad?
And you're still waiting for him
to come back?
Why would he come back?
He'll just go and find another idiot.
He already had what he wanted.
He'll come back.
He'll never come back!
Or let him come back...
And we'll take care of him,
just like they took care of Fuat...
What's this supposed to mean?
What do you think?
That he actually ran away?!
Why do you think
Narin ended up like this?!
They caught them at the Bride's Rock
and beat Fuat to death in front of her.
Get up.
They need help at Onur's field.
They're waiting for you.
What are you doing here?
l asked you to go to the fields to help.
They don't need me.
Do as you're told.
Back to the fields.
No.
You dare say no to your father?
Go to the fields!
The matchmaker found you a wife,
didn't she?
Let her bring the woman,
you'll take her to the fields.
Or better yet:
You go to the fields!
You're just like the others...
Go ahead.
Go away.
There's a fire!
Someone lit up the Bride's Rock!
Get up.
- l don't want to go.
Why?
Everyone's looking at me.
l'm too ashamed,
l can't cross the village.
How dare you show yourself here?
Fatma!
lf l were you l'd save my honor
and stay away from that harlot!
Then kill me too! There's no honor here,
there's no wolf up there and...
Shut up!
We're not telling you anything
because you're handicapped but if you...
That's enough!
Shut up!!